{
  "technologyQuestions": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "technology": "Python",
      "data": [
        {
          "id": 1111,
          "question": "What is the maximum possible length of an identifier?",
          "option": [
            "16",
            "32",
            "64",
            "none of these"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "none of these"
        },
        {
          "id": 1112,
          "question": "Who developed the Python language?",
          "option": [
            "Zim den",
            "Guido Van Rossum",
            "Nice Stom",
            "Wick Van Rossum"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Guido Van Rossum"
        },
        {
          "id": 1113,
          "question": "In which year was the Python language developed?",
          "option": [
            "1995",
            "1972",
            "1981",
            "1989"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "1989"
        },
        {
          "id": 1114,
          "question": "In which language is Python written?",
          "option": [
            "English",
            "PHP",
            "C",
            "All of these"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "C"
        },
        {
          "id": 1115,
          "question": "Which one of the following is the correct extension of the Python file?",
          "option": [
            ".py",
            ".python",
            ".p",
            "none of these"
          ],
          "correct_answer": ".py"
        },
        {
          "id": 1116,
          "question": "In which year was the Python 3.0 version developed?",
          "option": [
            "2008",
            "2005",
            "2000",
            "2010"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "2008"
        },
        {
          "id": 1117,
          "question": "What do we use to define a block of code in Python language?",
          "option": [
            "key",
            "brackets",
            "Indentation",
            "None of these"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Indention"
        },
        {
          "id": 1118,
          "question": "Which character is used in Python to make a single line comment?",
          "option": [
            "#",
            "!",
            "/",
            "//"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "#"
        },
        {
          "id": 1119,
          "question": "What is the method inside the class in python language?",
          "option": [
            "object",
            "function",
            "Attribute",
            "Argument"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "function"
        },
        {
          "id": 1120,
          "question": "Which of the following declarations is incorrect?",
          "option": [
            "_x=2",
            "__x=3",
            "__XYZ__=5",
            "None of these"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "none of these"
        },
        {
          "id": 1121,
          "question": "Why does the name of local variables start with an underscore discouraged?",
          "option": [
            "To identify the variable",
            "It confuses the interpreter",
            "It indicates a private variable of a class",
            "None of these"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "It indicates a private variable of a class"
        },
        {
          "id": 1122,
          "question": "Which of the following is not a keyword in Python language?",
          "option": [
            "val",
            "raise",
            "try",
            "with"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "val"
        },
        {
          "id": 1124,
          "question": "hgytryeyteryttyt",
          "option": [],
          "correctAnswer": "",
          "questionType": "programming"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "technology": "react",
      "data": [
        {
          "id": 3321,
          "question": "Which of the following is the correct name of React.js?",
          "option": [
            "React",
            "React.js",
            "ReactJS",
            "All of the Above"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "All of the Above"
        },
        {
          "id": 3322,
          "question": "Which of the following are the advantages of React.js?",
          "option": [
            "React.js can increase the application's performance with Virtual DOM.",
            "React.js is easy to integrate with other frameworks such as Angular, BackboneJS since it is only a view library.",
            "React.js can render both on client and server side.",
            "All of the Above"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "All of the Above"
        },
        {
          "id": 3323,
          "question": "Which of the following command is used to install create-react-app?",
          "option": [
            "npm install -g create-react-app",
            "npm install create-react-app",
            "npm install -f create-react-app",
            "install -g create-react-app"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "npm install -g create-react-app"
        },
        {
          "id": 3324,
          "question": "What of the following is used in React.js to increase performance?",
          "option": [
            "Original DOM",
            "Virtual DOM",
            "Both A & B",
            "none of these"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "virtual DOM"
        },
        {
          "id": 3325,
          "question": "A class is a type of function, but instead of using the keyword function to initiate it, which keyword do we use?",
          "option": [
            "Constructor",
            "Class",
            "Object",
            "DataObject"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Class"
        },
        {
          "id": 3326,
          "question": "Which of the following acts as the input of a class-based component?",
          "option": [
            "Class",
            "Factory",
            "Render",
            "Props"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Props"
        },
        {
          "id": 3327,
          "question": "Which of the following keyword is used to create a class inheritance?",
          "option": [
            "Create",
            "Inherits",
            "Extends",
            "This"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Extends"
        },
        {
          "id": 3328,
          "question": "What is the default port where webpack-server runs?",
          "option": [
            "3000",
            "3030",
            "8080",
            "6060"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "8080"
        },
        {
          "id": 3329,
          "question": "How many numbers of elements a valid react component can return?",
          "option": [
            "1",
            "2",
            "4",
            "5"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "1"
        },
        {
          "id": 3430,
          "question": "What is the declarative way to render a dynamic list of components based on values in an array?",
          "option": [
            "Using the reduce array method",
            "Using the <Each /> component",
            "Using the Array.map() method",
            "With a for/while loop"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Using the Array.map() method"
        },
        {
          "id": 3433,
          "question": "What is a state in React?",
          "option": [
            "A permanent storage.",
            "Internal storage of the component.",
            "External storage of the component.",
            "None of the above."
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Internal storage of the component."
        },
        {
          "id": 3432,
          "question": "What is a state in React?",
          "option": [
            "A permanent storage.",
            "Internal storage of the component.",
            "External storage of the component.",
            "None of the above."
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Internal storage of the component."
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "technology": "java",
      "data": [
        {
          "id": 5041,
          "question": "Which of the following option leads to the portability and security of Java?",
          "option": [
            "Bytecode is executed by JVM",
            "The applet makes the Java code secure and portable",
            "Use of exception handling",
            "Dynamic binding between objects"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Bytecode is executed by JVM"
        },
        {
          "id": 5042,
          "question": "Which of the following is not a Java features?",
          "option": [
            "Dynamic",
            "Architecture Neutral",
            "Use of pointers",
            "Object-oriented"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Use of pointers"
        },
        {
          "id": 5043,
          "question": "The ! article referred to as a",
          "option": [
            "Unicode escape sequence",
            "Octal escape",
            "Hexadecimal",
            "Line feed"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Unicode escape sequence"
        },
        {
          "id": 5044,
          "question": "_____ is used to find and fix bugs in the Java programs.",
          "option": [
            "JVM",
            "JRE",
            "JDK",
            "JDB"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "JDB"
        },
        {
          "id": 5045,
          "question": "Which of the following option leads to the portability and security of Java?",
          "option": [
            "Bytecode is executed by JVM",
            "The applet makes the Java code secure and portable",
            "Use of exception handling",
            "Dynamic binding between objects"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Bytecode is executed by JVM"
        },
        {
          "id": 5046,
          "question": "Which of the following is a valid declaration of a char?",
          "option": [
            "char ch = utea",
            "char ca = 'tea';",
            "char cr = ȣ",
            "char cc = itea"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "char ch = 'utea';"
        },
        {
          "id": 5047,
          "question": "What is the return type of the hashCode() method in the Object class?",
          "option": [
            "Object",
            "int",
            "long",
            "void"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "int"
        },
        {
          "id": 5048,
          "question": "Which of the following is a valid long literal?",
          "option": [
            "ABH8097",
            "L990023",
            "904423",
            "0xnf029L"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "0xnf029L"
        },
        {
          "id": 5049,
          "question": "What does the expression float a = 35 / 0 return?",
          "option": [
            "0",
            "Not a number",
            "Infinity",
            "Run time Exception"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Infinity"
        },
        {
          "id": 5050,
          "question": "Evaluate the following Java expression, if x=3, y=5, and z=10:++z + y - y + z + x++",
          "option": [
            "24",
            "23",
            "20",
            "25"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "25"
        },
        {
          "id": 5051,
          "question": "Which of the following tool is used to generate API documentation in HTML format from doc comments in source code?",
          "option": [
            "javap tool",
            "javaw command",
            "Javadoc tool",
            "javah command"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Javadoc tool"
        },
        {
          "id": 5052,
          "question": "Which of the following option leads to the portability and security of Java?",
          "option": [
            "Bytecode is executed by JVM",
            "The applet makes the Java code secure and portable",
            "Use of exception handling",
            "Dynamic binding between objects"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Bytecode is executed by JVM"
        },
        {
          "id": 5053,
          "question": "Which of the following creates a List of 3 visible items and multiple selections abled?",
          "option": [
            "new List(false, 3)",
            "new List(3, true)",
            "new List(true, 3)",
            "new List(3, false)"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "new List(true, 3)"
        },
        {
          "id": 5054,
          "question": "Which of the following for loop declaration is not valid?",
          "option": [
            "for ( int i = 99; i >= 0; i / 9 )",
            "for ( int i = 7; i <= 77; i += 7 )",
            "for ( int i = 20; i >= 2; - -i )",
            "for ( int i = 2; i <= 20; i = 2* i )"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "for ( int i = 99; i >= 0; i / 9 )"
        },
        {
          "id": 5055,
          "question": "In which process, a local variable has the same name as one of the instance variables?",
          "option": [
            "Serialization",
            "Variable Shadowing",
            "Abstraction",
            "Multi-threading"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Variable Shadowing"
        },
        {
          "id": 5057,
          "question": "WAP to print dynamic data ?",
          "option": [],
          "correctAnswer": ""
        },
        {
          "id": 5059,
          "question": "What is runtime polymorphism?",
          "option": [],
          "correctAnswer": "",
          "questionType": "programming"
        },
        {
          "id": 5061,
          "question": "what is compile time polymorphism?",
          "option": [],
          "correctAnswer": "",
          "questionType": "programming"
        },
        {
          "id": 5063,
          "question": "java oo java",
          "option": [],
          "correctAnswer": "",
          "questionType": "descriptive"
        },
        {
          "id": 5065,
          "question": "11111111111111111",
          "option": [],
          "correctAnswer": "",
          "questionType": "programming"
        },
        {
          "id": 5067,
          "question": "665431",
          "option": [],
          "correctAnswer": "",
          "questionType": "programming"
        },
        {
          "id": 5069,
          "question": "445324123123",
          "option": [],
          "correctAnswer": "",
          "questionType": "programming"
        },
        {
          "id": 5071,
          "question": "8976",
          "option": [],
          "correctAnswer": "",
          "questionType": "programming"
        },
        {
          "id": 5073,
          "question": "123141234234",
          "option": [],
          "correctAnswer": "",
          "questionType": "programming"
        },
        {
          "id": 5075,
          "question": "lalala",
          "option": [],
          "correctAnswer": "",
          "questionType": "programming"
        },
        {
          "id": 5077,
          "question": "JDBC",
          "option": [],
          "correctAnswer": "",
          "questionType": "descriptive"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "technology": "php",
      "data": [
        {
          "id": 7061,
          "question": "PHP stands for -",
          "option": [
            "Hypertext Preprocessor",
            "Pretext Hypertext Preprocessor",
            "Personal Home Processor",
            "None of the above"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Hypertext Preprocessor"
        },
        {
          "id": 7062,
          "question": "Who is known as the father of PHP?",
          "option": [
            "Drek Kolkevi",
            "List Barely",
            "Rasmus Lerdrof",
            "None of the above"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Rasmus Lerdrof"
        },
        {
          "id": 7063,
          "question": "Variable name in PHP starts with -",
          "option": [
            "! (Exclamation)",
            "$ (Dollar)",
            "& (Ampersand)",
            "# (Hash)"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "$ (Dollar)"
        },
        {
          "id": 7064,
          "question": "Which of the following is the default file extension of PHP?",
          "option": [
            ".php",
            ".hphp",
            ".xml",
            ".html"
          ],
          "correct_answer": ".php"
        },
        {
          "id": 7065,
          "question": "Which of the following is not a variable scope in PHP?",
          "option": [
            "Extern",
            "Local",
            "Static",
            "Global"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Extern"
        },
        {
          "id": 7066,
          "question": "Which of the following is correct to add a comment in php?",
          "option": [
            "& …… &",
            "// ……",
            "/* …… */",
            "Both (b) and (c)"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Both (b) and (c)"
        },
        {
          "id": 7067,
          "question": "Which of the following is used to display the output in PHP?",
          "option": [
            "echo",
            "write",
            "print",
            "Both (a) and (c)"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Both (a) and (c)"
        },
        {
          "id": 7068,
          "question": "Which of the following is the use of strlen() function in PHP?-",
          "option": [
            "The strlen() function returns the type of string",
            "The strlen() function returns the length of string",
            "The strlen() function returns the value of string",
            "The strlen() function returns both value and type of string"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "The strlen() function returns the length of string"
        },
        {
          "id": 7069,
          "question": "Which of the following is used for concatenation in PHP?",
          "option": [
            "+ (plus)",
            "* (Asterisk)",
            ". (dot)",
            "append()"
          ],
          "correct_answer": ". (dot)"
        },
        {
          "id": 7070,
          "question": "Which of the following starts with __ (double underscore) in PHP?",
          "option": [
            "Inbuilt constants",
            "User-defined constants",
            "Magic constants",
            "Default constants"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "Magic constants"
        },
        {
          "id": 7071,
          "question": "Which of the following is the use of strpos() function in PHP?",
          "option": [
            "The strpos() function is used to search for the spaces in a string",
            "The strpos() function is used to search for a number in a string",
            "The strpos() function is used to search for a character/text in a string",
            "The strpos() function is used to search for a capitalize character in a string"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "The strpos() function is used to search for a character/text in a string"
        },
        {
          "id": 7072,
          "question": "What does PEAR stands for ?",
          "option": [
            "PHP extension and application repository",
            "PHP enhancement and application reduce",
            "PHP event and application repository",
            "None of the above"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "PHP extension and application repository"
        },
        {
          "id": 7073,
          "question": "Which of the following is the correct way to create a function in PHP?",
          "option": [
            "Create myFunction()",
            "New_function myFunction()",
            "function myFunction()",
            "None of the above"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "function myFunction()"
        },
        {
          "id": 7074,
          "question": "Which of the following PHP function is used to generate unique id?",
          "option": [
            "id()",
            "mdid()",
            "uniqueid()",
            "None of the above"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "uniqueid()"
        },
        {
          "id": 7075,
          "question": "Which of the following is the correct way of defining a variable in PHP?",
          "option": [
            "$variable name = value;",
            "$variable_name = value;",
            "$variable_name = value",
            "$variable name as value;"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "$variable_name = value;"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}